Guide to the HaviKoro Crew Collection, 1983-2010 MS 652
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
HaviKoro Crew Collection
1983-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Havikoro
MS 652
2 Linear Feet 2 boxes + 1 map drawer of oversize materials
The HaviKoro Crew Collection contains T-shirts, posters, hand painted shoes, hand painted jacket, documents, oversized posters and banners.
Historical note
In 1999, two Houston based B-boy dance groups K.O.R.O (Knights of Rhythm Odyssey) and HAVIK (Having a Vicious Indestructible Krew) combined to create HaviKoro.
Their mission is to serve the underprivileged in the U.S. and around the world through their first-hand experience in dealing with life's tough challenges and difficult choices. The group's outreach focuses primarily on at-risk youth, offering positive messages via urban performance and sharing their testimonies and talents. In 2004, HaviKoro partnered with Houston's Association of American Voices and the U.S. State Department to perform in dozens of foreign countries, as the U.S. 'Hiplomats' representing the unique contribution of hip hop to American culture.
HaviKoro has competed in and won top level events around the world winning first place in the U.S. "Out for Fame" best crew contest (2001) and third place in the world "Battle of the Year" (Hannover, Germany, 2001).
The City of Houston honored HaviKoro and their contributions by proclaiming March 4, 2016 "HaviKoro Day."
Content Description
The HaviKoro Crew Collection contains T-shirts, posters, hand painted shoes, hand painted jacket, documents, oversized posters and banners.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was donated to Rice University through the Center for Engaged Research and Collaborative Learning (CERCL) in 2016.
Index Terms
Subjects
Music
Document Types
posters
Places
Texas--Houston; Art
- Series I. Promotional materials
  - Flyers/Programs (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - HaviKoro backstage pass, 2005 (Box 1)
  - HaviKoro International tour schedule, September 24-October 3, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - HaviKoro poster - signed (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Set List (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Signed Flag, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Summer Session poster - signed, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "We All Fall Up" Documentary poster, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - HaviKoro promotional banners and posters (Drawer 149)
- Series II. Clothing
  - HaviKoro chain, Brotherhood chain (Box 1)
  - Wild Style Hat, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bleedin' the Block t-shirt (2), July 28, 1983 (Box 1)
  - K.O.R.O t-shirt (Box 1)
  - HaviKoro Style t-shirt (Box 1)
  - "Everything's Fresher in Texas: Knights of Rythm Oddysey 10th Anniversary" t-shirt (Box 1)
  - HaviKoro t-shirt, 1999 (Box 1)
  - HaviKoro shoes - hand-painted shoe art create by artist Scriber, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Puma high-top sneakers (Box 2)
  - HaviKoro Jacket, 2008 (Box 2)